I'm a research lead of Operator in OpenAI.
And what is Operator?
Operator is a research preview of an agent
that uses browsers to, help user to do things.
So I have a two year old kid who likes pasta.
So I, make linguini with clams,
so I ask it to buy the groceries for it.
So I will use the Instacart app.
Operator can actually basically
use any website without...
And it is not particularly optimized
for Instacart.
But the reason why I’m using this app
is that it provides the,
detailed instruction
of how this website can be best utilized,
just like the tutorial
that humans can benefit from.
So I'll use Instacart tab and ask it to solve tasks
could you find a recipe of linguine with clams,
from Allrecipes website
and add all the ingredients
to the grocery cart,
or Instacart.
I think I already have,
some ingredients like butter
vegetable oil,
and black pepper.
So you don't need to add them to the cart.
So it says there I'll find recipe
and then add everything in the,
ingredients to the cart.
Okay, it says that, it’ll confirm
the ingredients
and store with me
before adding them to the cart.
So let's start by, finding the recipe.
I am not doing anything,
from now on.
Operator is just doing
and I am just watching what it’s doing.
What is interesting with Operator
is that its,
it is using browser
that I built for the human,
and it is using the, seeing the exactly
same script that I am seeing right now
and using the keyboard typing and mouse
clicking to control the browser.
Just like a human would do.
This is different from other agents
that uses,
API or programing based interface,
which programmers might understand,
but no programmer users cannot understand
it really well.
So Operator, because it is using the,
this natural human interface
it’s very easy to follow by just looking at what it's doing in the screen.
Can you follow its progress?
Yes! So one way to follow its progress
is I can zoom in to see the screen better.
And Operator is powered by the, text
based, chain of thought reasonings.
So whenever it is doing things, it, says,
it makes plans of how things can be done.
And this can be followed
through this, list of the tasks.
And it says I found the recipe. And,
which store would you prefer to use?
So I ask, use Gus’s.
So often
it asks clarifying question
whenever it is needed,
it has clarifying question
is needed in the process
of solving the task.
There are cases the Operator has to, make sensitive
actions like things like logging in or buying things.
In this case,
we built Operator to be safe in this situation.
So Operator is designed to ask, us
to take control,
to log in by ourselves
or whenever it needed, checking it.
It gives us the control
so that I can double check
or whether the list is correct
and then checking it by myself.
Amazing. Thank you so much.
I appreciate you showing it to us.
Thank you so much.